Officer Du.
‫أيها المدير دو
My brother did take away the firing pin.
أخي أخذ الحقنة
I don't know why the gun could be fired!
لا أعرف كيف فتحه
Officer Du.
أيها الضابط دو
Trust me,
ثق بي
neither of us killed anyone.
لم نقتل أحد
Officer Du!
أيها الضابط دو
Du!
شياو دو
Du Xiangdong.
دو شيانغ دونغ
Officer Du.
أيها المدير دو
You finally came to.
استيقظت
Easy, easy.
ببطء ببطء
How are you feeling? Are you hungry?
كيف تشعر بالجوع
What happened to me?
ماذا بي
Xu Wenguo knocked you out,
ضربك شو ون قوه حتى فقدت الوعي
so I carried you to the hospital.
لقد حملتك
He hit me?
اضربني
What happened to me?
ماذا بي
Xu Wenguo knocked you out,
ضربك شو ون قوه حتى فقدت الوعي
so I carried you to the hospital.
لقد حملتك
Who are you?
من أنت
Is this supposed to be fun, Du Xiangdong?
هل تمثلين مسرحية لنا دو شيانغ دونغ
He just came to.
استيقظت للتو
What is all this noise about?
ماذا تتشاجرون؟
The patient needs rest.
يحتاج المريض للراحة
Keep quiet, please.
حافظ على الهدوء
Nurse,
أيها الطبيب
what's my diagnosis?
ما خطبي؟
Concussions.
ارتجاج دماغ
Nurse, it seems like he has lost
أيها الطبيب يبدو أنه
some memories.
لا يتذكر الكثير
It's temporary amnesia caused by concussions.
فقدان الذاكرة القصيرة بسبب ارتجاج الدماغ
It's just normal.
كل شيء طبيعي
Does it mean he can't recall anything?
لا أتذكر أي شيء
It seems so.
يبدو
Du.
شياو دو
I lent you 30 yuan a few days ago.
لقد اقترضت مني ثلاثين يوان قبل بضعة أيام
Do you remember that?
هل تتذكر
Who is Du?
من هو شياو دو
Nurse, when will he
يا دكتور حالته هذه
recover his memories?
كم من الوقت يمكن أن يتعافى
In the best case, a day or two.
‫إذا كان سريعاً ليومين أو يومين‬
What about the worst case?
ببطء
You'll have to ask the doctor for specifics.
عليك أن تسأل الطبيب بالتفصيل
Will he act like this forever?
هكذا في المستقبل
I should've stuck to my strategy.
لا يجب تغيير
You should've laid down
ضعها بشكل صارم
those tiles earlier.
اخرج مبكرا
See,
أعتقد أنك
you worship bodhisatvas every day.
أنت هنا كل يوم
Why didn't you have any luck today?
لماذا لا تعمل اليوم
Stop with that distressing remark.
لا تقل هذا الكلام السيء
I'm done with it.
لا تضرب لا تضرب
I'm quitting.
لا
Come on. Fancy a drink?
هيا، هل تشرب؟
Join us. Come on.
تعال تعال
Don't go away. Come with us.
لا تذهب تعال تعال
Let's drink!
معا
Where are you going?
إلى أين سنذهب
Why are you running away?
لماذا تهرب
Come and drink with us.
لنشرب معاً
Ms. Cai,
أيها القائد ساي
why did they start practicing without me?
لماذا بدأت التدريب؟
Am I late?
هل تأخرت؟
I'll put on my costume right away.
يجب أن أغير ملابسي
Wait...
لا
Xinxin, why did you girls stop？
شين شين، لماذا لا ترقصن؟
Honghong,
هونغ هونغ.
come here.
هيا
I'm sorry that you're no longer
‫هذه الرقصة‬
part of the dance crew.
لا ترقص الآن
Sounds fine.
هذا جيد
I'm not familiar with some of the stage announcements.
لدي بعض الكلمات غير مألوفة في الصحيفة
I'll go memorize them outside.
سأحفظها في الخارج.
Honghong.
هونغ هونغ.
I've been informed
لقد تلقيت الخبر
the factory has also changed the announcer.
‫قام المصنع بتغيير الناس في هذه الصحيفة‬
Maybe you should go home, get some rest
عودي إلى المنزل واستريحي
and take care of your mother.
اعتني بأمك.
Honghong!
هونغ هونغ
You forgot your bag.
لم تأخذ حقيبتك بعد
Xinxin, Yue'er,
شين شين يوه
continue with the practice.
تعال للتدريب
You will get on the stage soon,
‫على وشك الصعود على المسرح‬
but today you're performing worse than yesterday.
‫لم أرقص بشكل جيد اليوم‬
Practice now.
أسرعي
Hurry up.
بسرعة
Stay focused.
انتباه
Xinxin, Yue'er.
شين شين، يوه أر
Let me get through!
افسحوا الطريق
The technical team has arrived
لقد وصل فريق التكنولوجيا
and conducted a preliminary examination.
وفحص الأولي
There aren't obvious
‫هذا الميت
fatal wounds on the victim's body,
‫لا يوجد جرح قاتل واضح
but bruise marks were found on her neck.
‫لكن على رقبته يوجد علامة مخنقة‬
Based on our current findings,
بالنظر إلى الوضع الحالي
we believe she was strangled to death.
‫يجب أن تكون مخنقة حتى الموت‬
We've collected a few fingerprints and several sets of footprints,
‫تم استخراج بعض بصمات الأصابع والبضع من آثار الأقدام
together with some fibers.
‫ووجدت بعض النظام
We'll conduct further analysis back in the lab.
استعد للعودة لإجراء تقييم أكثر
The first group of laid-off workers of Banan City's
مصنع السرير السادس في باران
No. 6 Machine Factory in 1993 is hereby announced.
قائمة المجموعة الأولى من العمال في عام 1993
Workshop One, Ding Huixiang.
‫ورشة السيارة دينغ هوي شيانغ
Workshop One, Wang Feisu.
‫غرفة العربة وانغ تشيان سو‬
Workshop One, Ding Biyun.
ورشة واحدة دينغ بي يون
Workshop One, Xiao Weiguo.
ورشة واحدة شياو وي دولة
Workshop One, Mei Xianzhi.
‫ورشة واحدة مي شيان تشي‬
Workshop Four, Chen Meixin.
‫المركز الرابع تشن مي شين‬
Workshop Four, Wang Jungu.
‫غرفة العربات الأربعة وانغ جيون قو‬
Quiet down, please.
هدوء
Everybody, quiet down!
هدوء الجميع
Quiet down.
هدوء هدوء
Alright?
حسنا
I have a few words to say.
استمعوا لي
Just listen, will you?
هل هذا جيد؟
As you can see,
الجميع رأى
now,
الآن
the factory is about to be restructured.
يجب إعادة تشكيل المصنع
I'm afraid you'll have to leave your old positions
‫لنغادر منصبنا المألوف أولا‬
and strive for
إلى هذا المجتمع
new opportunities
إلى السوق
in the society
‫هذا المسرح أكبر‬
and the job market where you might
‫في بحر أكبر‬
thrive.
‫للتجول‬
Alright?
أليس كذلك
What right do you have to decide who to be dismissed?
لماذا تقرر أي منصب تنزل
What about our livelihoods?
ماذا نأكل
These decisions are not made by me.
هذا ليس قراري
Quiet down!
هدوء
It's no use yelling.
لا فائدة من الشجار
We demand to talk to the party secretary!
نريد مقابلة المذكرة
The factory director and the party secretary
مدير المصنع والمكتب
have to deal with more important issues now.
لا يزال هناك شيء أكثر أهمية للقيام به الآن
I don't mind being sacked.
يمكنني أن أستقيل من العمل
But why do my parents have to be laid off too?
لماذا تجعل والداي يغادرون العمل أيضا
Don't you know
لماذا
the reason better than I do?
ألا يجب أن تعرف أكثر مني
People of your kind don't deserve a job here.
يجب أن يغادر هذا النوع من الأشخاص
Your whole family should be laid off.
يجب أن يتم استبعاد جميع العائلة
Her family brings shame to the factory.
‫عائلتهم تسببوا في الفخ في المصنع‬
They deserve to be laid off!
‫يجب أن يغادروا العمل‬
We firmly support the factory's decisions!
نحن بالتأكيد ندعم قرار المصنع
Good.
حسنا
Thank you for your understanding.
شكراً على فهمكم
As you can see,
لقد رأيتم
not everyone is unreasonable.
هناك شخص يعرف الحقيقة
If you really think about
آمل أن تفكروا جيدا
being made redundant,
هذا المنصب
Yonghong!
يونغ هونغ
you'll realize it is not necessarily bad.
ليس بالضرورة شيء سيء
She and her family should be laid off.
إن عائلتهما خارج العمل
But what have we done to deserve the same?
لماذا تطلب منا أن ننزل من العمل
We've been honest workers all the time.
لقد كنا صادقين طوال حياتنا
Why must we be laid off?
لماذا نطرد من العمل
We've done nothing wrong.
نحن نظيف
What's the reason for firing us?
لماذا يطلب منا الخروج من العمل
-Why?
لماذا لماذا
Everybody, please calm down!
اهدأوا
Yonghong.
يونغ هونغ
I'm also on that list.
العمة في القائمة أيضا
Take care.
على مهلك
Be careful!
ببطء
Yonghong...
يونغ هونغ
Yonghong, just stay there.
يونغ هونغ لا تتحرك
Don't step forward.
لا تتحرك لا تتحرك
Don't jump off it.
لا تقفز
I'm worried about you.
لا تخيفني
What will happen
ستموت
to your parents if you die?
ماذا عن والديك؟
Have you taken their feelings into consideration?
هل فكرت في مشاعرهم
Xu Wenguo!
شو ون قوه
Xu Wenguo, where are you?
شو ون قوه أين أنت
Take me away!
خذني بعيدا
Wenguo...
ون قوه
Mom.
أمي
Dad.
‫أبي
Tang Yaoxin insisted on paying you a visit.
‫تانغ ياو شين أصر على زيارتكم
Here they are.
‫انظر
Move the table forward.
حرك هذه الطاولة للأمام
I'll place it here.
‫تحركوا هنا‬
Get that board over here.
‫نقل هذه اللوحة إلى هنا‬
This?
هذا
Do you need any help?
أختي هل تريدين أن أساعدك
No, it's okay. I got this.
لا بأس أنا هنا
And then what?
ثم
Lay it down horizontally.
‫غطي على سطح‬
This is my bed,
هذا سريري
where I sleep.
سأنام هنا
Now you've seen it.
لقد رأيتها
It's time you left.
لنذهب
I'd like a room.
‫فندق‬
For how many people?
كم أنت؟
Just one.
واحد
For how many nights?
كم يوما
Only one.
ليلة واحدة
Five yuan for one night.
خمس يوان الليلة
Show me your ID.
تعال بطاقة الهوية
I lost it.
ضاعت
I can't proceed without your ID.
ليس من السهل التعامل مع عدم وجود بطاقة الهوية
I need to put down your information.
لقد سجلت هذا
Then I won't stay here.
لا أريد البقاء
I can fix the problem.
لا بأس لا بأس
Pay me another five yuan, and I'll rent you a room.
سأعطيك خمسة يوان أخرى
That's more like it.
هذا صحيح
Come here, Qiaoqiao!
‫تعال تشياو تشياو‬
Yes.
‫أنا قادم‬
Take this gentleman to his room.
‫تعال خذه معنا‬
Make way, please.
افسحوا الطريق
Here's the key.
تعال المفتاح
Shall we?
هيا
Come on, keep up.
بسرعة
Why are you so slow?
لماذا أنت بطيء
Keep going.
هيا
This way.
من هنا
Here!
هنا
Why are you standing there?
ماذا تفعل
Come here.
تعال
Here it is.
وصلنا
Come on in.
ادخل
It's freezing cold outside.
الجو بارد بالخارج
Sit down.
اجلس
Mister,
أخي
we provide massages here.
خدمة التدليك هنا
10 yuan per hour.
عشرة يوان ساعة
Professional service.
محترف
Would you like to give it a try?
هل تريد أن تجرب
This is all I have.
هذا كل ما لدي
Take it.
خذها
You can go now.
انزل
But I haven't served you yet.
لم أطبخ لك
How can I take your money?
كيف يمكنني أخذ أموالك؟
Just leave.
انزل
All I want is a good sleep.
أريد فقط أن أنام
Fine, mister.
حسنا يا أخي
How about this?
هكذا
I'll stay here for only half an hour.
سأجلس هنا لمدة نصف ساعة
You can sleep as you want.
أنت تنام
They'll give me a hard time if I show up downstairs now.
وإلا لن أستطيع أن أشرح لك
Just a while, okay?
حسنا يا أخي
You look really tired.
يبدو أنك متعب
Get some sleep now, will you?
نامي قليلا
Mister!
أخي
You sit there.
اجلس
You look exhausted.
يبدو أنك متعب جدا
Let me give you a massage.
دعني أدلك
A head massage for fatigue relief.
لتخفيف التعب وتضغط على رأسك
Are you feeling cold,
هل تخاف من البرد؟
mister?
أخي
Well,
إذا
at least take off your glasses.
اخلع نظارتك
Who would sleep with glasses on?
من يرتدي نظارات أثناء النوم
Let me give you a massage.
دعني أدلك
I'll put the glasses beside you.
سأضعه بجانبك
Don't be so tense, mister.
لا تتوتر يا أخي
Do you like this?
ما رأيك في طبخ أختي؟
We spent days investigating and found
بعد عدة أيام من زيارتنا
that Chen Su'e
تشين سو يا
had gone back to her hometown in Mengcheng
منذ قضية ياو بين بين
after testifying in court
في المحكمة
for Yao Binbin's case.
عدت إلى مسقط رأس منغ تشنغ
She secluded herself
ولم يخرج إلا بعد
and seldom interacted with others.
‫لا تتواصل مع الغرباء
On the day of her death,
في يوم الحادث
her neighbors
الجيران المحيطين
didn't hear any unusual sounds.
لم أسمع أي صوت غير طبيعي
Captain,
أيتها القائدة
we compared the fingerprints
بعد أن حصلنا على بصمات الأصابع
with those of the people Chen Su'e knew.
مقارنة مع كل من يعرفه تشين سو يا
Two of the three fingerprints
اكتشفت أن هناك اثنين من الأصابع
match Xu Wenguo's.
هناك اثنان من البصمات من شو ون قوه
Who?
من
Whose are they?
لمن
Xu Wenguo.
شو ون قوه
We compared
بعد أن أخذنا هنا
the fingerprint records of Xu Wenguo here
الملف عن بصمات الأصابع شو ون قوه
with the fingerprint photos taken
والصور بصمات الأصابع لعائلة تشين سو يا
in Chen Su'e's home,
في منزل تشين سو يا
and found a perfect match.
اكتشفنا أن الأمر متطابق تمامًا
Chen Su'e refused to
لا بد أنه بسبب تشين سو يا
provide an alibi for Xu Wenguo and his brother,
رفض إثبات عدم وجوده
so he held a grudge against her.
شو ون قوه يكره في قلبه
After he escaped,
بعد الهروب
he went to her place and killed her.
ذهبت إلى منزل تشين سو يا لقتلها
I beg to differ.
لا أظن ذلك
After all, Chen Su'e watched
بعد كل شيء تشاهد تشين سوا ا ا
Xu Wenguo and Yao Binbin grow up.
نشأ شو ون قوه و ياو بين بين
Resentful though Xu Wenguo might be,
حتى لو كان لديه كراهية في قلبه
it was unlikely for him to kill her.
قد لا يستطيع فعل ذلك
Wait a moment.
انتظر
Two of the three fingerprints
ثلاث بصمات
belong to Xu Wenguo.
اثنان لشو ون قوه
Whose is the remaining one?
من آخر
We haven't figured it out yet.
لم نجد بعد
The evidence we've obtained suggests
حسب الأدلة التي حصلنا عليها الآن
that Xu Wenguo was at the crime scene,
ذهب شو ون قوه إلى مسرح الجريمة
and is a major suspect.
وهناك مشتبه به كبير
How is he doing now?
كيف حاله الآن
He is doing fine.
حالته الحالية جيدة
His condition is stable.
مستقر جدا
Sorry.
آسف
I was held up by work in the factory.
لقد تأخرت بعض الأمور في المصنع اليوم
It's alright. No worries.
لا بأس لا بأس
How is the patient now?
ماذا يحدث الآن؟
He is asleep in the ward.
إنه نائم في الداخل الآن
Our office is just right in front.
مكتبنا في الأمام
Let us know if you need help.
اتصلوا بنا إذا احتجتم أي شيء
-Alright? -Got it. Thank you.
حسنا حسنا شكرا
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة
Alright, go see him then.
حسنا اذهب بسرعة
I'm heading back to the center.
سأعود إلى مركز الشرطة
Thank you so much.
شكراً لك.
Chief.
سيدي المحترم.
Well,
حسناً
the application form?
استمارة الطلب
Thank you for reminding me.
لقد نسيت إذا لم تخبرني
I already prepared it for you.
لقد أعددت لك منذ وقت طويل
Have you two reached a consensus?
لقد تناقشتما من قبل
You must think it through.
يجب أن تفكر جيدا
I've made up my mind.
لقد فكرت في الأمر
Thank you, Chief.
شكراً لك أيها المدير
Li.
لاو لي
Su.
لاو سو
Xiangyang.
شيانغ يانغ
Who are you looking for?
من تبحث
Du Xiangdong.
دو شيانغ دونغ
For what?
لماذا تبحث عن دو شيانغ دونغ
An important issue.
لدي شيء مهم
Something important is going on there too.
هناك شيء مهم في الداخل
His girlfriend is with him.
جاءت حبيبته
Give them some privacy.
دع الشباب يبقوا وحدهم لبعض الوقت
I'm carrying police duties.
لدي مهمة
What's the thing?
ما هي مهمتك؟
This is serious.
لقد وقعت في مشكلة
Chen Su'e was murdered.
قُتل تشين سو يا
Xu Wenguo's fingerprints
وجدت بصمات الأصابع
were found in her home.
بصمات شو ون قوه
What does it have to do with Du Xiangdong?
ما علاقة هذا بـ دو شيانغ دونغ
Xu Wenguo used his badge
شو ون قوه أخذ
when he escaped.
هرب بسبب بطاقة الشرطة
You know about
‫أمر بطاقة الشرطة‬
that badge stuff.
أنتم تعرفون
He didn't give it to Xu Wenguo on purpose.
لم يقصد إعطاء شو ون قوه
What are you all doing here?
ماذا تفعلون
This is a hospital.
هنا مستشفى
Please keep quiet.
هدوء
My apologies.
آسف آسف
He was attacked
لقد أصيب
when he was chasing after a fugitive.
‫ثم أصيب بالهجوم من قبل اللصوص‬
It was a meritorious act.
هذا هو أداء إنجاز
We shouldn't falsely accuse a fellow of ours.
لا يمكننا أن نظلم زملائنا
What meritorious act?
ما هو الإنجازات؟
Why did he have to do that?
لماذا قبض على هارب؟
Did I ask him to chase after a fugitive?
هل أحتاج إلى القبض على هارب؟
If he hadn't interfered,
إذا لم يسبب المشاكل
we might have caught Xu Wenguo.
قد نقبض على شو ون قوه
You're right.
نعم نعم
As criminal police officers,
ماذا عنكم؟
all you handle is serious cases,
‫فريق الشرطة الجنائية يقوم بعمل كبير‬
unlike us.
‫ليس مثلنا‬
You see,
انظر
he's my old schoolmate and he never listens to me.
إنه زميلي لكنه لا يستمع إلي
Aren't you going to discipline him as his superior?
أنت قائدته هكذا
Are you incapable of managing
لا يمكنك التحكم به
your subordinates or what?
أم لا؟
He simply can't rein in Xiangdong.
لا يمكنه التحكم به
What's the point of meeting him now?
ما فائدة دخولكم الآن؟
He doesn't recognize you.
إنه لا يعرفكم
Let me handle it, alright?
دعني أهتم
How?
كيف؟
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا
I'll have him watched 24/7.
سأرسل خصيصا لمراقبته لمدة 24 ساعة
I promise he won't go out to cause trouble,
لن أسمح له بالخروج لإثارة المتاعب
or to show his face before your eyes.
ولن يظهر أمام أعينكم
I'll ask the brass
هناك
for permission.
سأتقدم بطلب
I guarantee you with my 30-year party membership.
أضمن عمري ثلاثين سنة
Su,
لاو سو
we two go way back.
لقد عرفنا بعضنا البعض لسنوات عديدة
You know me well.
أنت تعرفني
You'd better keep your word.
من الأفضل أن تفي بوعدك
Otherwise,
وإلا
we'll discipline him for you.
سنهتم بك
This is what the higher-ups want.
هذا ما يريده الرؤساء
I don't get a say in it.
لا أستطيع التحكم
I understand.
فهمت فهمت
I'm leaving then.
سأذهب
Liu Fenfang, I'm hungry.
ليو فنفانغ أنا جائع
You already woke up.
استيقظت
What would you like to eat? I'll get it for you.
ماذا تريد أن تأكل سأحضر لك
What are you looking at?
إلى ماذا تنظرين؟
Don't you know who I am?
ألا تعرفني؟
Did you just call my name?
لقد ناديتني للتو
Do you have another name I don't know?
هل لديك اسم آخر؟
Nurse!
أيتها الممرضة
Nurse, he can recognize me!
‫أيها الممرضة، هل تعرفه؟
Have you recalled everything?
هل تذكرت كل شيء
Do you feel pain in the head?
هل رأسك يؤلمك؟
No need to cry, right?
لماذا تبكين
Why are your hands so cold?
لماذا يدك باردة جدا
I was worried sick!
لقد أخفتني
I thought you would
اعتقدت أنك
never remember me.
لا يمكنك التعرف علي
Is he awake now?
استيقظت
Nurse, check him out.
أيتها الممرضة، ألقي نظرة
What's your name?
ما اسمك
Du Xiangdong.
دو شيانغ دونغ
What's her name?
ما اسمها
Her name is Liu Fenfang.
اسمها ليو فنفانغ
Good progress.
تعافيت بشكل جيد
His brain has almost recovered.
لقد تعافيت تقريباً
Sign him up for a checkup just to make sure.
اذهب للفحص والتأكيد
Nurse.
أيتها الممرضة
Will this injury affect his future children?
هل سيؤثر جرحه على الجيل القادم
Liu Fenfang, I heard you.
ليو فنفانغ سمعت
Because I did say it.
نعم
Thank you.
شكرا
Thank you, nurse.
شكراً لك أيتها الممرضة